Ashwini Lalitha Huchahanumegowda

Phone: 512 739 0807 | Email: <u>ashwini.lh12@gmail.com</u> <u>GitHubRepo</u> | <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>Portfolio Page</u>

Summary

Passionate and solutions-driven full stack web developer with a web development certificate from University of Texas Austin and Master's degree in Electrical Engineering from VTU, Belagavi, India. Proactive in learning new technologies with core competency in full-stack development and gaining experience and knowledge in the field of software engineering.

Core Proficiencies / Tools

Languages:

Web development: JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, Handlebars.js, ReactJs, AngularJs, Node.js, Express.js.

Source Control: GitHub

DBs: MySql, MongoDB

Other/Open Source: BootStrap, Bulma, Climatiq API, OpenWeatherMap API, Heroku

Code Editor: Visual Studio Code

Project Experience (April 2022 - now)

Cars2GoDeployed URL: Cars2GoTeam Size: 3GitHubRepo

- Cars2Go website enables customers to browse through Cars2Go Store inventory, the website displays all the cars with basic information like make, model, milage, price and condition.
- Cars2Go website also enables employees to login and add, remove or update to the existing inventory.
- Worked in collaboration with team members tasked with backend API's creation, model, creating database tables and seeding the database, creating stories, maintaining git branches, pull request approval.

Environment/Tools: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Handelbars, Heroku, MYSQL, Expressjs, Nodejs, Sequelize

Carbon Footprint CalculatorDeployed URL: Carbon-FootPrintTeam Size: 4GitHubRepo

- Carbon Footprint By Region is Front end app, where you can calculate carbon foot print for activities like electricity usage, clothing and foot wear.
- Collaborated with team to identify the API's for calculating the carbon foot print, use of CSS framework, making the API
 call with right tokens and inputs and hosted the app on Heroku.

Environment/Tools: HTML, CSS, and Javascript, Bulma, Climatiq API, and Carbon Interface API.

 Weather Dashboard
 Deployed URL: Weather Dashboard
 Team Size: 1
 GitHubRepo

- Weather dashboard allowed users to enter a city name and see it weather for next 5 days.
- The dashboard also provided a list of recently searched cities.
- The data for the dashboard was from the OpenWeatherAPI.

Environment/Tools: jQuery, JavaScript, Bootstrap, OpenWeatherMap API.

Education / Training / Recognition

- Certificate in Full Stack Web Development University Of Texas, Austin April 2022- October 2022
- Master of Technology(Power System Engineering) Visveswaraya Technological University, India 2015

Professional Experience

Lead Teacher – Primrose School Jan 2021 – Jan 2022

Working as a lead teacher in charge of pre-kindergarten. Guide children to develop their artistic and practical capabilities through a curriculum. Employ a variety of educational techniques to teach children.

Volunteer Teacher – Parinama Academy Oct 2018 – Feb 2019

Assisted elementary school kids with basic chess and math. Also volunteer at RRISD and LISD, helped school kids with chess and math after school hours.

Lectured subjects like Operations Research, Energy Auditing, Transmission and Distribution. These subjects involved use of mathematical models, statistics, differential equations and algorithms.

Lead Lab Instructor for Direct Current and Synchronous machines – This involved application of mathematics to problems in electrical machines and the development of mathematical methods suitable for such applications and for the formulation of electrical theories.

Mentored around 20 students during my tenure providing proper career guidance and counseling.